if you're watching this video it's
because you want to make money trading
Forex but there's one tiny little
problem you're not profitable clearly
cuz you're watching this video you're
trying to become profitable but don't
worry there's a solution in this video
I'm going to teach you the easiest and
the fastest way to become profitable in
2024 and this is what I like to call the
one strategy you know if like if you
have a girl she's the one or if you have
a guy he's the one well this is the one
strategy that will make you profitable
and that is you guys it's one pattern
one session and one trade a week it's
going to all make sense and this video
there's no everything's
straight up to the point so let's get
into it so first things first I need you
to understand that the first thing with
the strategy is that you will only be
trading one pattern so it's going to be
very simple and very straightforward to
understand it and you will only be
looking for this one pattern every
single day this is going to be the
pattern that is going to make you
successful and will be the pattern that
pretty much repeats itself time and time
and time again in the market you're not
going to be trading with other types of
pattern you will only be using one
single pattern and this pattern will
have about a 65 to 70% win rate of the
time because this pattern happens time
and time and time again and it is only a
pattern you're not going to be using
indicators you're not going to be using
other tools you're not going to be using
RSI da all this stuff that pretty much
puts stuff on top of the pattern which
gives it an edge no you will only be
sticking to the pattern on its own so
you're probably wondering why you only
need to take this one pattern and that
is because the market has thousands of
opportunity but that doesn't mean that
you have to take every single trade the
market gives thousands of opportunities
for different types of strategies and
those different type of strategies they
have different types of Entry signals
they have different type of risk reward
strategies they have different types of
take profits different types of stop
losses everything is different and every
single different strategy has a
different trading plan for this one is
going to be one specific one so you
don't need to use these other ones or
take a little bit from here and apply it
to another one every single trading plan
and every single pattern is different
and it requires a different type of
approach so you have to make sure you
have the proper equation to apply to
this successful pattern so you can
actually make money the problem a lot of
traders that they do is they see all of
these different opportunities in the
market and they want to get all of them
at the same time or as many as possible
thinking that that's how you're going to
make more money the more trades you take
and the more patternss you take and the
more trading plans you have doesn't mean
the more money you're going to make it
actually means the more money you're
going to lose because you're actually
involved in the market more when when in
the market actually less is more because
the less you're involved in the market
that means that you're only getting
involved in successful types of Trades
the more you're involved in the market
that means you're prone to more risk
which at the end of the day more losses
and the simplest example that I can put
for this is a surfer when you go out
there to be a surfer you're not going to
surf every single wave that the ocean
gives you you're going to literally get
exhausted and you probably won't have a
high surf rate or success rate riding
the wave to the beach because there's so
many different types of wave that you
don't know if it's a small one a big one
because you're just constantly trying to
get on every single wave so you probably
won't be able to ride every single one
because you're currently on one wave
then you can't get off of one then get
on one there's just too much going on if
you're trying to Surf every single wave
but let's say that you're a surfer and
you're just sitting there in the water
waiting for that one big wave
well once that one big wave comes you
see it coming from afar you avoid all
the little ones that make no sense and
once you get on that one big wave your
surf rate will be a lot higher the it
will be a lot smoother you can do more
tricks it'll be more worth the while and
more enjoyable having one solid wave a
day or a week rather than having to
crash on a bunch of little waves in the
middle of the ocean for no reason so now
you're probably wondering what pattern
this is right and you've actually seen
this pattern hundreds of time and you
will continue to see it this pattern is
known as break and retest now just don't
think that you know how to use it just
yet because there's actually a strategy
behind how to use it what time frame
what session and what entry signal is
exactly what I'm going to explain in
this video so the pattern itself of the
one strategy will be the break and
retest strategy sounds simple right well
that is because simple works in the
market but if you use it effectively and
if it's your first time hearing this
break and retest and you're wondering
what it is this is what it is it
literally is a break and retest like
that's it's literally that simple and it
might sound too simple but it is what it
literally says it's when something
breaks it it comes back it rets it to
continue to the upside or to the
downside this pattern Works obviously
both ways a breakout to the upside or a
breakout to the downside this is where a
market is usually at a level of
accumulation and it will break up to
create a high it'll come back and retest
the previous Market structure to then
continue heading to the upside or if you
have a breakout to the downside this is
where the market will then have a
breakout to the downside it will then
retest the previous structure point or
the support and resistance which we'll
get into all that now so then it
continues heading to the downside this
is a very classic move and this pattern
happens time and time again you can
enter in two different types of formats
in this trade you can enter on the
actual breakout of the pattern or you
can enter on the actual retest but I'm
going to explain a little bit more of
this when we get to the actual entry of
how you can use the break and retest and
how to have the successful win rate and
break and retest are everywhere like you
see that right there yeah that says hit
the Subscribe button all right so with
that being said and now that you
understand that how can you actually
visualize break and retest well we
probably breaking retest every single
day in our day-to-day lives and you're
probably wondering what the hell does
that mean well we literally break in
retest when we're going up steps or when
we're going down steps every single time
you're going up a step in stairs you're
breaking the last step to retest that
step so it can get you to the next one
it's a continuation climb to the upside
and when you're going down the steps are
down the stairs you're using the last
step as your support so you can put your
foot on the next step so you can
continue heading to the downside the
market does the same exact steps to the
upside and the same exact steps to the
downside now you're going to use the
steps in your favor to have the break
and retest to then go up and then your
break and retest to go down you cannot
go to the steps to the second floor
without using the break and retest and
you cannot go down from the second floor
to the first without using the break and
retest to the downside and now this is
very key that you understand this
because this is going to lead you to
understanding how to become profitable
as fast as possible why because this
pattern happens every single day so you
can capitalize off of it more often than
a normal person would cuz when a number
of person sees it they just think oh
it's another break and retest but they
don't really think about capitalizing
behind
so if you have to make sure that you
understand this pattern because it's
going to be the fastest way how you can
actually make money and that leads me to
my next point which is how is it the
easiest well the easiest is because
we're going to actually see this pattern
every single day and that is by using a
very specific time frame which will lead
you to seeing it every single day and
that is going to be the 30 minute time
frame this will be the time frame that
you're going to be looking for on this
break break and retest and it will be
the only time frame that you will be
looking for this pattern now this
pattern happens on the 1 hour the 2 hour
the 4 Hour the daily the 15 minute the 5
minute the 1 minute all of these
different time frames it will happen but
this pattern will take a lot longer to
happen in obviously the higher time
frames and this pattern on any time
frame below the 30 minutes simply won't
be as respected as on the 30 minute I've
been trading now for 7 years and I've
literally tried to put this a test many
times and it's just not as effective
it's more effective on the higher time
frames it just requires a lot more
patience and it requires for you to be
in the trade longer and the pattern
doesn't happen as frequently as it would
on the 30 minute and that is why it's
extremely important you only focus on
the 30 minute time frame and yes this
pattern once again is on every time
frame but it is not as effective as it
is on the 30 minute this is very
important to not only having the fastest
way to become profitable but so it is
the most effective so now that you know
what the pattern is which is break and
retest and you know at what time frame
you should be looking for it which is on
the 30 minute and you go onto the market
and you see this pattern happen time and
time again you're probably wondering
when should you enter the trade when is
the right time is it in the morning is
it in the afternoon is it in the evening
when should I enter the trade and the
answer is you should only enter the
trade at two different sessions the
market has four different sessions two
of them having the best liquidity two
having no liquidity liquidity is when
the market has a lot of volume when
there's a lot of buyers and sellers in
the market which is going to drive the
market in a direction faster than the
other this is why you only want to take
this trade when you see this pattern
either in the New York session or the
London session these are the only
sessions where your trade and this break
and retest pattern is going to have the
60 to 65% win rate because this is where
the market is going to go in your favor
faster with with the volume versus not
now the market does have this breaking
retest pattern outside of the New Yorker
London session because the break and R
pattern happens that frequently but you
should not be taking a trade in that
session because there is no volume the
Market's not going to move as fast and
the pattern isn't as respected on the
sessions without volume compared to the
ones that it does and the simplest
analogy that I can put with this is very
simple and it's actual staircase once
again right so remember the break and
retest pattern is going to happen every
single day no matter what and same way
how the stairs are going to be there no
matter what so you get from the first
floor to the second floor the second
floor to the third floor whatever you
know level floor you want to use now
depending on the time of the day let's
say it's rush hour and you want to get
from the first floor to the second floor
you have to go through the steps a lot
faster because there's somebody behind
you and somebody in front of you so you
have to rush up the stairs so you're
break and retesting each step to get to
that second floor will happen a lot
faster versus if you go up those steps
let's say at midnight there's really
nobody going up the stairs at that time
so you can take your time going up the
steps well that's exactly how it works
with the market when the market is break
and retesting in New York session or
London session there's a lot of traffic
there's a lot of movement so it actually
happens a lot faster compared to if it
were to do that pattern at a different
session when there's not a lot of people
so you don't want to be entering a break
and retest trade when there's nobody at
at the stairs because it's going to move
a lot slower you want to enter it when
there's a lot of people at the stairs so
your trade can move in your direction a
lot faster you have to remember the more
volume that means that the bigger the
candlesticks are you don't want to be
taking a trade when the volume is little
bit because the candlesticks are going
to be very very very small you want to
take a trade when the candlesticks are
going to be very big so it can go into
your takeprofit a lot faster than it
would in these other sessions therefore
you're going to make a lot more money
which is going to be the fastest way and
the easiest way on how to make money
with a break and retest pattern because
you can still make money on a low
session volume but it's not ideal
because it's not the fastest or the
easiest you're going to be in a trade
for a long period of time where it can
mess with your psychology when you can
just simply be waiting for the right
session to kick in where you can get
that big Candlestick in your favor or in
the other direction now that leads us to
our next point which is going to be what
is the actual entry confirmation now
that we know that it's a break and reach
p pattern and we know it's on the 30-
minute time frame and we only take the
trade in New York or London session what
is the entry signal how do I know it's
the right entry confirmation to get into
the trade well it's actually very very
simple there's two different types of
entries you can have in order for you to
enter this trade the first one is going
to be the initial breakout of your break
and retest pattern so when you have a
market that has been consolidating at a
specific Zone on the 30 minute time
frame for more than 4 hours you're going
to little box accumulate now inside of
this accumulation box you can enter the
first trade which will be the breakouts
now the breakout has to be confirmed on
the closure of the Candlestick when it
breaks out of the zone you cannot enter
the breakout trade if the Candlestick
has not closed above the zone you need
to make sure that the Candlestick has
closed with a bullish engulfing above
the zone or a bullish engulfing below
the Zone this is going to be your
confirmation that the market has had a
breakout right this is the first
indication because if the Candlestick
hasn't closed yet it's not a confirmed
breakout the market can still have a
pullback and close as a big wick
continuation the rejection of the
consolidation box where the market is
potentially about to break out meaning
that now once you have your body
Candlestick that has closed above or
under the zone you are now ready to
enter the first position which is going
to be your bullish engulfing or bearish
engulfing confirmation this is where you
want to have your entry point right at
the closure of that Candlestick and then
you want to have your stop loss under
the zone of where the bottom of the
consolidation box is is going to be key
because just in case the price decides
to come back into the zone and retest
the bottom of the box your price is
still good and you do not get stopped
out this is very important because this
way if the Market has another entry
confirmation you can enter at the retest
and I'm going to get into that point
right now but you have to make sure that
you have your entry at the closure of
the Candlestick above and your stop loss
under the box if you're buying and if
you're selling you make sure that you
have your stop loss above the zone and
then your entry confirmation at the
bearish engulfing Candlestick so this is
your first entry which is the breakout
if for whatever reason you missed the
breakout entry this is where the retest
comes in because usually when price has
a break it comes back and it retests
price because remember the stair example
you have to use each step to go on to
the next one so this is where price
usually has a retest of the zone of the
same exact spot where it's was having a
struggle to break out and then this is
where you would wait for your next
bullish engulfing if you're buying or a
bearish engulfing if you're selling but
you make sure you have to wait for the
retest or also known as the pullback
where the market is going to have a push
a pullback and then that is where you
enter the trade to the upside or to the
downside you have a break you have a
retest or a pullback and then it
continues to head to the downside that
is going to be your second entry only if
you missed the first one you do not want
to scale in into two positions kind of
at the same Zone simply won't make any
sense so where you enter this trade at
the retest same exact thing when it
comes to stop-loss placement you want to
make sure that your stop- loss is under
the Zone where it was trapped in if
you're buying you want to make sure that
your stop loss is above the Zone where
it was trapped in if you're selling
simple so far right I'm sure all of you
guys can remember moments when you've
seen the market do this or you can just
simply open a chart really fast and
you're going to see this pattern 100
times but there's a catch there's one
catch that's how you have to subscribe
no I'm kidding no I mean you could if
you want but whatever uh the point is
that the catch is that you can only take
one of these trades a week now I know
that's hard we come from a background
the more trades we take the more money
we will make but that is not how this is
going to work you only want to take one
break and retest trade a week why well
this is because since this pattern
happens so many times why shouldn't you
take all of them and the answer is
because you only want to take the best
one how do you make sure you only take
the best one by only taking one and this
is going to be very key to your win rate
and to how fast you become profitable
because if you're only taking the best
of the best trades well you you should
have the best of the best results it's
almost like a sniper you're only taking
one good shot versus like a machine gun
that you're just shooting a bunch of
different targets at the same time you
want to make sure you shoot one good
shot with precision and good aim not
just random Fire at every single object
that appears and that is why at the
beginning of the video I said that you
do not take every single opportunity the
market has to give you even if you get 5
10 breaking retest in the same day you
only take the best ones that matter this
is how you're going to become profitable
the fastest way and the easiest way
because you're only focusing on what's
going to make you money how easier is
that going to get and what faster than
only taking one trade a week on a
pattern that happens every single day
like I I can't make this any easier and
patterns like these I see them every
single week in the market and not only
do I make money with them but every
single student that gets on a call with
me every single Sunday where I give them
the pairs that I'm going to be trading
and how they can use the patterns that
I'm seeing the market that's going to
play out this week where it's going to
make them anywhere from ,000 to $1,500 a
week as a beginner Trader all of the
students that apply the set and forgas
strategy make anywhere from $1,000 to
$11,500 a week using the set and forgas
strategy now if you've never heard about
the set foret strategy like how you
potentially didn't know how to become
profitable the fastest or the easiest
way just click the link in the
description below I have a video there
for you that explains to you exactly
what set and forget is and how it's let
students make numbers like these or even
these so if you want to know more about
it make sure you click the link in the
description below and that's where
students are making anywhere from $1,000
to $1,500 a week as a beginner set and
forget Trader I hope this video was
useful and you to become one of the
fastest and easiest traders to become
successful and I'll see you guys in the
next video